How about Miss Peach?
미스 피치는 어떻습니까?
Did I buy the right thing?
내가 제대로 구매한 걸까?
The captain asked me to give it to His Majesty the Emperor
선장은 나에게 그것을 황제 폐하께 전해 달라고 부탁했습니다.
The fake death medicine
가짜 죽음의 약
But it's very complicated
하지만 매우 복잡해요
If you can't find it
찾을 수 없다면
All the medicinal materials
약재의 모든 것
This medicine just won’t work.
이 약은 효과가 없습니다.
inside
내부에
I still need a lot of medicine.
아직 약이 많이 필요해요.
But the medicinal shop in the market
그런데 시장에 있는 약가게
I've been all over
난 다 가봤어
Those medicinal herbs you want?
당신이 원하는 그 약초?
I really can’t buy it anymore
진짜 이제 못 사겠다
Otherwise
그렇지 않으면
Let me accompany you to the mountains to collect medicinal materials.
산에 가서 약재를 모으도록 해주세요.
I was there some time ago
나는 얼마 전에 거기에 있었다
Prepared a poison
독약을 준비했어요
As long as someone gets it on you
누군가가 당신에게 그것을 얻는 한
It will be extremely itchy
엄청 가렵겠다
I'd rather take the antidote
차라리 해독제를 먹는 게 낫겠어
Developed
개발됨
Just suffer from
그냥 고생해라
No one has tried it for me yet
아직 아무도 나를 위해 시도해 본 적이 없습니다.
I don’t know if it’s useful or not.
유용한지 아닌지는 모르겠습니다.
Then let me try
그럼 나도 한번 해볼게
This will be very itchy
이거 엄청 가렵겠다
I'm not kidding you
농담하는 게 아니야
What if my antidote doesn't work?
해독제가 효과가 없으면 어떻게 되나요?
You'll at least get itchy
적어도 가려워질 거야
Three days and three nights
사흘 낮과 사흘 밤
It's okay, peach girl
괜찮아 복숭아 아가씨
I trust you
나는 당신을 신뢰합니다
OK
좋아요
That's it
그게 다야
Since you helped me try the antidote
내가 해독제를 시험해 볼 수 있게 도와준 이후로
The medicinal materials Shiqirou asked for
Shiqirou가 요청한 약재
I will definitely prepare it for you as soon as possible
최대한 빨리 준비하겠습니다.
good
좋은
I know you love sweets
당신이 과자를 좋아하는 걸 알아요
Come and try this Tang Cai Su
와서 이 Tang Cai Su를 시험해 보세요.
Which store did you buy this from?
이거 어느 매장에서 샀어요?
This is not bought
이건 구매한 게 아니다
Miss Gu just sent it over
구 선생님이 방금 보냈어요
She made it specially for you
그녀는 당신을 위해 특별히 그것을 만들었습니다
Of course not
당연히 아니지
A Yuan Lao Bao and the others all have it
A Yuan Lao Bao와 다른 사람들은 모두 가지고 있습니다.
I remember you like to eat
당신이 먹는 걸 좋아했던 기억이 나네요
I brought it here specially for you
널 위해 특별히 가져왔어
take a taste
맛을 보다
Put it here
여기에 넣어
I'll eat it later
나중에 먹을게요
Fine
괜찮은
correct
옳은
I've already contacted everyone in Kyoto.
나는 이미 교토에 있는 모든 사람들에게 연락했습니다.
Everything is ready now
이제 모든 준비가 끝났습니다
I only owe east wind
나는 오직 동풍만을 빚지고 있다
The medicine is at Taozi's place
약은 도자 집에 있다
Not ready yet
아직 준비가 안 됐어요
I know
알아요
I let Chang Er follow her every day
나는 Chang Er에게 매일 그녀를 따라오게 했다
See what I can do to help
제가 무엇을 도와드릴 수 있는지 알아보세요
Ask Xie Changer to help Taozi
Xie Changer에게 Taozi를 도와달라고 요청하세요
I think it would be better not to cause more trouble
더 이상 문제를 일으키지 않는 것이 좋을 것 같아요
It's okay to cause chaos
혼란을 야기해도 괜찮습니다
Save her from always being next to you
그녀가 항상 당신 옆에 있지 않도록 구해주세요
I'm afraid she'll prick me with a poisonous needle
그 사람이 독침으로 나를 찔릴까봐 두렵다.
good
좋은
Why did she stab you with a poisonous needle?
왜 그녀는 독침으로 당신을 찔렀습니까?
Because
왜냐하면
Let's break camp
캠프를 쉬자
Live here with Zhenxijun
Zhenxijun과 함께 여기서 생활하세요
Enough inconvenience
불편함은 충분히
Even if we set up camp outside today
오늘은 밖에 캠프를 차려도
Have to move out too
이사도 나가야하고
yes
예
I suddenly remembered
문득 생각났어요
Our son
우리 아들
I love this snack the most
나는 이 간식을 가장 좋아한다.
I will send it to the young master now
지금 젊은 스승님께 보내드리겠습니다.
I brought you snacks specially
특별히 간식을 가져왔어요
How do you give it to someone else?
다른 사람에게 어떻게 주나요?
Isn't that someone else gave it to you?
그건 다른 사람이 준 거 아닌가요?
You just brought it to me
방금 가져오셨어요
Grand Governor
총독
Chinzei Army Hwa Choi Family Army
진제군 최화가문군
Join hands to conquer the capital
손을 잡고 수도를 정복하세요
Fu Yuan'er died in the city
Fu Yuan'er는 도시에서 사망했습니다.
this
이것
Cui Jiajun didn't immediately
Cui Jiajun은 즉시 그렇지 않았습니다.
Return to Yingzhou
잉저우로 돌아가기
Also joined forces with the Zhenxi Army
진희군과도 합세
Attack Luoyang
낙양 공격
Cui Yi's son Cui Lin
추이의 아들 추이린
Look at his past behavior
그 사람의 과거 행동을 보세요.
You know he is very calm
그 사람 아주 침착한 거 아시죠?
If the war situation at that time were me
당시의 전쟁 상황이 나라면
I will definitely attack Luoyang first
반드시 낙양을 먼저 공격하겠습니다
Save Yingzhou again
잉저우를 다시 구해주세요
But Luoyang City is strong
하지만 뤄양시는 강해요
Sufficient food and grass
충분한 식량과 풀
Fu Yuan'er just needs to hold on and not come out
Fu Yuan'er는 버티고 나오지 않아야합니다.
Chinzei Army Hwa Choi Family Army
진제군 최화가문군
That’s ten times more powerful
10배는 더 강력해요
It's absolutely impossible
절대 불가능해요
Destroy the city in a short time
짧은 시간 안에 도시를 파괴하세요
and
그리고
Fu Yuan'er is a veteran on the battlefield.
Fu Yuan'er는 전장의 베테랑입니다.
How could it be
어떻게 그럴수있어
Defeated at the hands of two children
두 아이의 손에 패배
Lost this battle
이번 전투에서 졌습니다
It's my fault in hiring people
사람을 고용한 건 내 잘못이야
This loss of Luoyang
낙양의 손실
It gave me a wake-up call
그것은 나에게 모닝콜을 주었다
Strong enemies are nothing but external forces
강한 적은 외부의 힘일 뿐이다
What can really destroy oneself
정말로 자신을 파괴할 수 있는 것은 무엇인가
Often it’s the inside
내부인 경우가 많습니다
This West Changjing seems to be impregnable
이 서쪽 창징은 난공불락 인 것 같습니다
I'm afraid there are also loopholes
허점도 있을까봐
I'll send someone to check it out.
사람을 보내 확인해 보겠습니다.
Kyoto aristocratic families
교토 귀족 가문
Be careful to prevent him from secretly colluding with the rebels
그가 반란군과 비밀리에 결탁하지 않도록 조심하세요.
The person who secretly colludes
몰래 공모하는 사람
Not just in aristocratic families
귀족 가문뿐만 아니라
Seventeenth Lang Cui's army broke out of camp
제17군 랑취의 군대가 진영에서 탈출했다
What break camp
무슨 휴식 캠프
right
오른쪽
school lieutenant
학교 중위
It's almost all sorted out
거의 다 정리됐네요
I'll go for a walk by the river
나는 강가로 산책하러 갈 것이다
I'll go with you
나는 당신과 함께 갈 것이다
No
아니요
You should be busy first
먼저 바빠야지
good
좋은
Collect everything inside quickly
안에 있는 모든 것을 빠르게 수집하세요.
Yes Yes
예 예
No matter what you say, don't say a word
무슨 말을 해도 아무 말도 하지 마세요.
I suddenly have to break camp and move out of the city.
갑자기 캠프를 중단하고 도시 밖으로 이동해야 합니다.
How does our Cui Jiajun behave?
우리 Cui Jiajun은 어떻게 행동합니까?
I have to report it to the emperor’s grandson.
황제의 손자에게 보고해야 해요.
That's not true
그건 사실이 아니야
Just walking in a hurry
그냥 서둘러 걷는 것 뿐이야
I remember not being able to give you a ride
태워주지 못했던 기억이 나네요
Think of it again
다시 생각해 보세요
You will be returning to Yingzhou soon
곧 잉저우로 돌아올 예정입니다.
From now on, the mountains are high and the rivers are far away
이제부터 산은 높고 강은 멀다
I don’t know when we can meet again
우리가 언제 다시 만날 수 있을지 모르겠어요
Then I promise you
그럼 약속할게
Before I go back to Yingzhou
영주로 돌아가기 전에
I must come and say goodbye to you properly
꼭 가서 제대로 작별인사를 해야지
you said
당신은 말했다
How did this happen?
어떻게 이런일이 일어 났습니까?
There are so many wolves in Laolan Guan
라오란관에는 늑대가 너무 많아요
Every time I go out of town and meet a wolf
동네에 나가서 늑대를 만날 때마다
We will do it casually
우리는 아무렇지도 않게 할 것이다
Pick up a stone to kill the wolf
늑대를 죽이려면 돌을 집으세요
It’s been a long time
오랜만이야
Everyone has learned this skill
모두가 이 기술을 배웠습니다.
Whenever I have free time
여유 시간이 있을 때마다
will be by the Laolanguan River
라오랑관 강 옆에 있을 거예요
in vain
헛된
Where's the winner?
승자는 어디에 있나요?
The first piece of roasted lamb belongs to him
구운 양고기의 첫 번째 조각은 그의 것이다
sounds really interesting
정말 흥미로운 것 같아요
Want to try it?
그것을 시도하고 싶습니까?
Come
오다
not far enough
충분하지 않다
I teach you
나는 당신을 가르친다
hold
잡고 있다
It's done
끝났다
So that's it
그래서 그게 다야
Jushichiro
주시치로
Cui Li came to see me
Cui Li가 나를 만나러 왔어요
Cui Li
리 추이
This person has great ambition but little talent
이 사람은 야망은 크지만 재능은 적다
And the villain has no moral integrity
그리고 악당은 도덕적인 고결함이 없어요
Do anything for power
권력을 위해서라면 뭐든지 해라
how
어떻게
What does he want from you?
그 사람이 너한테 원하는 게 뭐야?
He wants to join forces with us to kill Cui Lin
그는 우리와 힘을 합쳐 추이린을 죽이려고 합니다
General Pei
페이 장군
I intend to join forces with the Zhenxi Army
나는 진시군과 힘을 합칠 생각이다
Kill Cui Lin
추이린을 죽여라
You are not afraid
당신은 두려워하지 않습니다
I tied you up
내가 너를 묶었지
Send it to Master Cui
Master Cui에게 보내세요.
Please be honest
솔직하게 말해주세요
On the matter of killing Cui Lin
추이린 살해 문제에 대해
The positions of you and me
너와 나의 입장
It should be consistent
일관성이 있어야 한다
From Wangzhou to Luoyang
왕저우에서 뤄양까지
There should be quite a few of my cousins
내 사촌들이 꽤 많이 있을 텐데
I'll cause you trouble
내가 널 곤란하게 만들 거야
without him
그없이
You have the food and grass
당신에게는 음식과 풀이 있습니다
This city
이 도시
You have already taken it
이미 가져가셨군요
General Pei
페이 장군
Haven't you ever thought about it?
그것에 대해 생각해 본 적 없나요?
Cutting off the roots
뿌리를 자르다
Get rid of this serious problem?
이 심각한 문제를 제거하시겠습니까?
I can assure you below
아래에서 확신할 수 있습니다.
Wait until Cui Lin dies
추이린이 죽을 때까지 기다리세요
This Cui family army is under my control
이 Cui 가족 군대는 내 통제하에 있습니다
When the time comes, I will definitely support the emperor’s grandson
때가 되면 반드시 황제의 손자를 지지하겠습니다.
Take the lead of Zhenxi Army and look forward to it
Zhenxi 군대를 이끌고 기대하십시오
After it's done
완료된 후
Luoyang is under my control
낙양은 내 통제하에 있다
how
어떻게
Open your mouth and ask for Luoyang
입을 벌려 낙양에게 물어보세요
You have a big appetite
당신은 식욕이 왕성해요
General Pei
페이 장군
This Luoyang is after restraint
이 낙양은 구속 후입니다
Chinzei military service available for direct entry
친제이 병역 직접 입국 가능
Go straight to Naxi Changjing
나시창징으로 직진
By then
그때까지
You can kill Sun Jing
손징을 죽일 수 있다
That traitor
그 배신자
The whole world belongs to the emperor's grandson
온 세상이 황제의 손자의 것이다
Naturally, the Dayu Dynasty can be restored
당연히 다유 왕조가 복원될 수 있다
I will still care then
그때도 난 신경 쓸 거야
Is it just a Hangdu?
그냥 항두인가요?
Yeah
응
That's it, it's settled
그렇군요, 해결됐네요
I'm bold
나는 대담하다
I also want to ask the general for a token
나도 장군에게 토큰을 요청하고 싶다
What token
어떤 토큰
I would also like to trouble you to write a handwritten letter from the emperor’s grandson.
그리고 황제의 손자가 직접 쓴 편지를 쓰시도록 부탁드리고 싶습니다.
After everything is done
모든 작업이 완료된 후
That Luoyang is controlled by me
낙양은 내가 통제한다고
how
어떻게
Little General Pei
작은 페이 장군
What does this mean
이것은 무엇을 의미 하는가
Cui Gongzi
추이 공즈
I want His Royal Highness’s handwriting
전하의 글씨체를 원해요
We also have to see if we can kill Cui Lin.
또한 추이린을 죽일 수 있는지도 살펴봐야 합니다.
You didn't do anything
넌 아무것도 하지 않았어
I just want handwriting
난 그냥 손글씨를 쓰고 싶어
I'm afraid it's not appropriate.
적절하지 않은 것 같습니다.
yes
예
Yes Yes Yes
예 예 예
The general is right
장군님 말씀이 맞습니다
Not as good as this
이것만큼 좋지는 않아
Below
아래에
Go and get Cui Lin’s men first.
가서 추이린의 부하들을 먼저 구하세요.
After everything is done
모든 작업이 완료된 후
Then ask for tokens from the emperor’s grandson
그런 다음 황제의 손자에게 토큰을 요청하세요.
How about this
이건 어때
Let’s talk about it then
그럼 얘기해보자
Such a villain
이런 악당
Cui Lin must be informed
추이린에게 알려야 합니다
Let him be careful
그 사람 조심하게 놔둬
Jushichiro
주시치로
I know what you are going to say
나는 당신이 무슨 말을 하려는지 알아요
But I still want to be upright
하지만 난 그래도 당당해지고 싶어
Fight him on the battlefield
전장에서 그와 싸워라
I don't want to see him
나는 그 사람을 보고 싶지 않아요
Injured by a villain's hidden arrow
악당의 숨은 화살에 부상을 입다
peach girl
복숭아 소녀
This is Shishiro
시시로입니다
To Captain He
선장에게
There's also this
이것도 있어요
This is what I give you
이것이 내가 당신에게 주는 것입니다
What's this
이게 뭐야?
pig ear
돼지 귀
I ran several streets
여러 거리를 뛰어다녔어
Just bought it
방금 샀어요
Still hot
여전히 뜨겁다
I do not want
하고 싶지 않다
But didn’t you say that last time?
그런데 저번에 그렇게 말하지 않았나요?
do you like eating it
그것을 먹는 걸 좋아하니?
I don’t want to eat it now
지금은 먹기 싫다
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
I have been with the captain these days
나 요즘 캡틴이랑 같이 있었어
Lived outside the city
도시 외곽에 살았습니다.
You feel
기분이
Are you feeling uncomfortable?
불편함을 느끼시나요?
No no
아니 아니
The medicine you gave me is quite good
당신이 준 약은 꽤 괜찮아요
I was itchy for two days and it was fine.
이틀동안 가려웠는데 괜찮아졌어요.
this is for you
이건 널위한거야
Apply three times a day
하루에 세 번 적용
This time the medicine is guaranteed to be effective
이번에는 약의 효과가 보장됩니다
Thank you Miss Peach
고마워요 미스 피치
What what?
무엇 무엇을?
Pig ears
돼지 귀
This girl suddenly wants to eat again
이 여자 갑자기 또 먹고 싶어지네
Give
주다
The girl’s family is so strange
그 소녀의 가족은 정말 이상해요
school lieutenant
학교 중위
Letter from His Royal Highness the Emperor
황제 전하의 편지
Why are you so happy?
뭐가 그렇게 기뻐?
No
아니요
What do I have to be happy about?
나는 무엇 때문에 행복해야 하는가?
Isn't it because of the ears?
귀 때문 아닌가요?
What ears?
무슨 귀?
Aren't those pig ears?
돼지 귀 아닌가요?
school lieutenant
학교 중위
make fun of me
나를 놀려
I won't let you eat
너한테 밥 못 먹게 해줄게
Aying
아잉
I heard there are rebels in the Cui family army
추이 가문 군대에 반군이 있다고 들었는데
Desire to kill Mr. Cui
추이 씨를 죽이려는 욕망
Possible conspiracy
가능한 음모
You and the young master, please pay more attention to your left and right sides.
당신과 젊은 스승님은 왼쪽과 오른쪽에 더 많은 관심을 가져 주시기 바랍니다.
Cherish it again after farewell
이별 뒤에 다시 소중히 간직해
from today
오늘부터
Add another bodyguard
다른 경호원 추가
Protect the young master
젊은 주인을 보호하세요
The march to Yingzhou is complicated.
잉저우로의 행진은 복잡하다.
Be sure to protect it
꼭 지켜주세요
Prince's safety
프린스의 안전
yes
예
My subordinates will make arrangements now.
이제 내 부하들이 준비할 것이다.
Aying
아잉
Why did I suddenly remember
왜 갑자기 생각났지
I need to increase my bodyguards
경호원을 늘려야지
The young master received a tip
젊은 주인은 팁을 받았습니다
Cui Li wants to be unfavorable to the young master
Cui Li는 젊은 스승에게 불리해지기를 원합니다.
Our army is about to break camp
우리 군대가 막사를 무너뜨리려 하고 있어요
The prince's safety
왕자의 안전
It must be the top priority
최우선 사항이 되어야 합니다
Ying, don’t worry about me
잉, 내 걱정은 하지 마
Continuous marches are hard work
계속되는 행진은 힘든 일이다
You think too much
당신은 너무 많이 생각
You should take good care of yourself
너 자신을 잘 돌봐야 해
It is my duty to consider the young master
젊은 스승을 배려하는 것이 나의 의무이다
You
너
peach
복숭아
help me get this letter
이 편지를 받을 수 있게 도와주세요
Leave it to Xie Changer
셰체인저에게 맡겨주세요
What's wrong
뭐가 문제 야
You've been making fun of me lately
당신은 최근에 나를 놀렸어요
I won't send you any more letters
더 이상 편지를 보내지 않겠습니다
You don’t want to send the letter?
편지를 보내고 싶지 않아?
Still don’t want to see Xie Changer
아직도 Xie Changer를 보고 싶지 않습니다.
I
나
What if it's the latter?
후자라면 어떨까요?
So I have it on the letter
그래서 편지에 써놨어
Add one more sentence
한 문장 더 추가
tell them
그들에게
Let Lao Bao come to deliver letters from now on.
이제부터 라오바오가 편지를 배달하러 오게 해주세요.
Don't mess with our peach girl
우리 복숭아 소녀를 건드리지 마세요
unhappy
불행한
look at you
당신을 보면
Then they are all the same.
그러면 그들은 모두 똑같습니다.
It doesn’t matter who gives it to you
누가 주든 상관없어
Let me do it
내가 하게 해줘
Then you go early and come back early
그럼 일찍 갔다가 일찍 돌아와라
Don't bully your ears
귀를 괴롭히지 마세요
Who bullied him?
누가 그를 괴롭혔나요?
Hard-spoken
딱딱한 말투
The emperor's grandson is asleep
황제의 손자가 잠들어 있다
Captain He will never come again
캡틴 그는 다시는 오지 않을 거예요
I'm afraid I'll have to sleep until night
밤까지 잠을 자야 할 것 같아
Just woke up
방금 일어났다
All over the place
모든 곳에
Where is Shi7ro really?
Shi7ro는 실제로 어디에 있습니까?
You can all be at ease
다들 안심하셔도 돼요
It’s because the breeze at this moment is like a fan
지금 이 순간의 바람은 선풍기 같아서
Grass and trees are fragrant
풀과 나무는 향기롭다.
You fell asleep
당신은 잠들었습니다
Fell asleep
잠 들었다
why do you want to remind me
왜 나에게 상기시키고 싶어?
Cui Li
리 추이
It will be detrimental to our young master.
그것은 우리 젊은 주인에게 해로울 것입니다.
Because I reminded you
내가 상기시켜줬으니까
You will definitely reply and come to see me
반드시 답장을 주시고 나를 만나러 오실 거예요
If I were to choose
내가 선택하라고 한다면
I won’t ask you to meet me
만나자고 하지 않을 거예요
Then I'll ask you to meet
그럼 만나자고 할게
I'm going back to Yingzhou
영주로 돌아갑니다
I promised you a good farewell
좋은 이별을 약속했어요
It's raining
비가 온다
take you somewhere
너를 어딘가로 데려가줘
OK
좋아요
Unexpectedly, the emperor's grandson
뜻밖에도 황제의 손자가
We also prepared such a room
우리도 이런 방을 준비했어요
That's natural
그건 당연해요
Fortunately, I have this house to take shelter from the rain
다행히 비를 피할 수 있는 집이 있어서
otherwise
그렇지 않으면
We will become drowned chickens
우리는 익사한 닭이 될 것이다
The emperor's grandson looks like a drowned rat
황제의 손자는 물에 빠진 쥐처럼 생겼다
It's not like I haven't seen it before
예전에 본 적이 없는 건 아닌 것 같은데
What a coincidence
이런 우연이
The girl looks like a drowned rat
그 소녀는 물에 빠진 쥐처럼 생겼어요
I've seen it a few times
나는 그것을 몇 번 본 적이 있다
The fragrance is refreshing and slightly bitter in the mouth.
향은 상쾌하고 입안에서는 약간 쓴맛이 납니다.
A different flavor
다른 맛
Is this bamboo leaf tea?
이거 대나무잎차인가요?
That's right
좋아요
What about the folk?
사람들은 어떻습니까?
Bamboo leaves are often used as a decoction instead of tea.
대나무 잎은 차 대신 달임약으로 자주 사용됩니다.
The status of the emperor's grandson is so valuable
황제의 손자의 지위는 너무나 귀중하다.
But he knows country life well
하지만 그 사람은 시골 생활을 잘 알아요
Is this life alive?
이 생명이 살아있는 걸까요?
Identity or something
신분인가 뭔가
least worth mentioning
언급할 가치가 가장 적은
So what if you are the emperor?
그렇다면 당신이 황제라면 어떨까요?
It’s not just a bowl of rice and a cup of tea
그냥 밥 한 그릇, 차 한 잔이 아닌
I think
제 생각에는
Be a farmer here
여기서 농부가 되어 보세요
Live more happily
더 행복하게 살아요
but have you ever thought about
그런데 생각해 본 적 있어?
If the emperor has no way
황제가 방법이 없다면
Farmers are displaced
농부들은 쫓겨났습니다
Even a simple meal
간단한 식사라도
It has become a luxury
명품이 되었어요
What's the point of having fun?
재미있게 놀면 무슨 ​​소용이 있나요?
do not know either
둘 다 모른다
Is there a bowl of rice here?
여기 밥 한 그릇 있나요?
can fill
채울 수 있다
The belly of our farmer
우리 농부의 배
All ready
다 준비됐어
This is also good
이것도 좋다
This won't work
작동하지 않습니다.
I'm not good at cooking
나는 요리를 잘하지 못한다.
If you don't mind
괜찮으시다면
I'll show you my hands
내 손을 보여줄게
Seventeen Lang cooks himself
세븐틴 랭이 직접 요리해요
How dare I despise it?
내가 어떻게 감히 그것을 경멸합니까?
but
하지만
I don't seem to know much about anything
나는 아무것도 모르는 것 같다.
Make a fire
불을 피우다
I should be able to light a fire
불을 피울 수 있어야 해
Okay, that's it.
알았어, 그게 다야.
Let me take a look
한 번 볼게요
Unexpectedly, the emperor's grandson
뜻밖에도 황제의 손자가
Prepared such comprehensive ingredients
이렇게 종합적인 재료를 준비했어요
I'm afraid you're hungry
배고프지 않을까 걱정돼
You really know how to cook
요리를 정말 잘 아시네요
What's this
이게 뭐야?
We are at Laolan Pass
우리는 Laolan Pass에 있습니다
Laundry, Hunting, Sewing and Cooking
세탁, 사냥, 바느질, 요리
Don’t you do it all by yourself?
혼자서 다 하지 않나요?
Then when you were in Laolan Pass
그러다 라오란 고개에 있었을 때
Didn't you bring a maid?
하녀 안 데려왔어?
If I want to bring a maid with me
메이드를 데리고 가고 싶다면
With me in Kyoto
나와 함께 교토에서
Life in the palace
궁에서의 생활
What's the difference
차이점이 뭐야
As the grandson of the emperor
황제의 손자로
But I don’t like the palace
하지만 나는 궁전을 좋아하지 않는다
A life of luxury and good food
호화로운 삶과 좋은 음식
That's interesting
그 흥미 롭군요
And me
그리고 나
He is an evil son born in the evil moon
사악한 달에 태어난 사악한 아들이다
Since childhood, the late emperor and his father
어린 시절부터 고 황제와 그의 아버지
don't like me
나를 좋아하지 않는다
Such fine clothes and fine food
이렇게 좋은 옷과 좋은 음식이라니
It’s okay not to
그러지 않아도 괜찮아
Turn on the bellows and light the fire
풀무를 켜고 불을 붙입니다
good
좋은
set fire to fire
불을 지르다
It's what I'm best at
그게 내가 제일 잘하는 일이야
Pulling boxes to light a fire
불을 붙이기 위해 상자를 당기는 모습
You also need to pay attention to skills
스킬에도 주의를 기울여야 합니다
Push it in slowly
천천히 밀어넣으세요
Then slowly pull it out
그런 다음 천천히 당겨 빼내세요.
Push it in slowly and pull it out
천천히 밀어넣었다가 빼내세요
anything else
다른 것
Let me try
나 해보자
The heat is very particular
더위가 참 특이해요
Don’t be big and small suddenly
갑자기 커지거나 작아지지 마세요
Dishes cooked like this
이렇게 조리된 요리들
It doesn't taste good
맛이 없어요
Do not worry
걱정 하지마
Come
오다
Here comes the rice.
밥이 나오네요.
Eat
먹다
Such a crude person
이런 뻔뻔한 사람
You even went to pick wild flowers?
야생화 따러 간 적도 있나요?
This is a humble house, but I am virtuous and kind.
이곳은 겸손한 집이지만 나는 고결하고 친절합니다.
Jushichiro
주시치로
You cooked this meal seriously
이번 식사는 진지하게 차려주셨네요
How can you deal with it casually?
어떻게 무심코 처리할 수 있나요?
The food is mediocre
음식은 평범해요
I feel wronged to you
나는 당신에게 억울함을 느낀다
how
어떻게
tasty
맛있는
Then you should eat more
그럼 더 먹어야지
You are not afraid
당신은 두려워하지 않습니다
I poisoned the food
나는 음식에 독을 넣었다
Of course I'm afraid
물론 두렵습니다
So just now
그럼 지금 막
When I was lighting the fire
불을 피웠을 때
Poisonous smoke has been released
유독한 연기가 방출되었습니다.
imperial grandson
황실 손자
You are now poisoned
당신은 이제 중독되었습니다
this is delicious
이거 맛있다
This is what I'm good at
이게 내가 잘하는 거야
Come
오다
Eat more of this
이것 좀 더 먹어봐
tasty
맛있는
Come
오다
Smash it for me
나를 위해 그것을 부숴주세요
Smash this vixen's nest
이 암여우의 둥지를 부수어라
stop
멈추다
Stop it
그만해요
Mrs. Wei
웨이 부인
This is the harem
여기가 하렘이야
How can I allow you to be so presumptuous here?
여기서 어떻게 당신이 그렇게 주제넘게 행동하도록 허용할 수 있습니까?
You also know this is the harem
너도 여기가 하렘인거 알지?
Then she, the former princess
그렇다면 그녀는 전 공주였지
Why are you still in this harem?
왜 아직도 이 하렘에 있는 걸까요?
It's you vixen
너야말로 암여우야
Charming Governor
매력적인 주지사
Disaster for the country and the people
나라와 국민의 재앙
It was you who caused my brother to be captured
내 동생을 사로잡은 건 너였어
I have to tear it apart today
오늘은 찢어야 해
You vixen is not allowed
너 여우야는 허락되지 않아
Give me back my brother
내 동생 돌려줘
open
열려 있는
I kill you
나는 당신을 죽인다
Give me the governor and let me go
나에게 주지사를 주고 나를 보내주세요
Tell my brother to let me go
형한테 놔달라고 말해
I have to kill you today
오늘은 널 죽여야 해
The governor has arrived
주지사가 도착했습니다
let me go
날 보내줘
Someone coming
누군가 온다
Mrs. Wei is sick
웨이 부인이 아프다
Help her down
그녀를 도와주세요
Call the doctor quickly
빨리 의사한테 전화해
yes
예
Grand Governor
총독
let me go
날 보내줘
Everybody stand down
다들 자리에서 일어나
Grand Governor
총독
how
어떻게
You are hurt
당신은 상처를 입었습니다
I feel wronged to you
나는 당신에게 억울함을 느낀다
I am not wronged
나는 잘못한 것이 없다
I had known it would be today
오늘이 될 줄 알았어
How could I be wronged?
내가 어떻게 부당한 대우를 받을 수 있겠습니까?
I've been thinking about it these days
요즘 계속 고민하고 있어요
then
그 다음에
If I take you away
내가 널 데려가면
What would that be like?
그건 어떨 것 같나요?
Think back to the beginning
처음부터 다시 생각해 보세요.
I am at the Ten Mile Pavilion outside the city
나는 도시 외곽의 Ten Mile Pavilion에 있습니다.
I've been waiting for you all day
난 하루 종일 당신을 기다리고 있었어요
until the sun goes down
해가 질 때까지
I didn’t see you coming either
너도 오는 걸 못 봤어
I knew it
알고 있었어
you will never come again
당신은 다시는 오지 않을 것입니다
Although at that time
비록 그 당시에는
I have been chosen as the Crown Princess
나는 왕세자비로 선택받았습니다
But as long as you are willing to take me away
하지만 당신이 나를 기꺼이 데려가려고 하는 한
I can
저 할 수 있어요
I'll fly away with you
나는 당신과 함께 날아갈 것이다
incognito
가명
Even if they are a poor and humble couple
가난하고 미천한 부부라 할지라도
I'm happy with it too
나도 만족해요
I failed you
나는 당신을 실망시켰다
No
아니요
I know too
나도 알아
You have a noble mother
당신에게는 고귀한 어머니가 계십니다
I have a weak younger brother and younger sister
나에겐 약한 남동생과 여동생이 있다
If you really take me away
정말 날 데려가면
That is the grave crime of being executed by a whole family.
그것은 온 가족이 처형당하는 중대한 범죄입니다.
I am guilty now
나는 지금 유죄입니다
But just think of it
하지만 생각해 보세요.
the days with you
너와 함께한 날들
Even if it's stolen
도난당하더라도
As long as I can be with you
내가 당신과 함께 있을 수 있는 한
No matter who scolds me
누가 욕해도 상관없어
Still spurn me
아직도 나를 쫓고 있어
I'm so happy
너무 행복해요
General Han
한 장군
We are now far from West Changjing
우리는 이제 서창징에서 멀리 떨어져 있습니다.
Is it already very far away?
벌써 너무 멀어졌나요?
Already thousands of miles away
이미 수천 마일 떨어진 곳에
Just a galloping horse
그냥 질주하는 말
It will take more than ten days
열흘 이상 걸릴 듯
The last thing my mother-in-law told me was
시어머니가 나에게 마지막으로 하신 말씀은 다음과 같다.
Aze, run away quickly
아제 빨리 도망쳐
The further away the better
멀수록 좋다
But General Han
하지만 한 장군은
I don't want to run away anymore
더 이상 도망치고 싶지 않아
I am the eldest son of the prince
나는 왕자의 장남이다
I am the grandson of the imperial dynasty
나는 제국 왕조의 손자입니다
but now
그러나 지금
I feel like a mouse every day
매일 쥐가 된 기분이야
Hiding in Tibet
티베트에 숨어
I told His Highness
나는 전하에게 말했다
The story of General Han Xin
한신 장군의 이야기
I also told the story of Gou Jian, King of Yue.
나는 또한 월왕 구견(Gou Jian)의 이야기를 들려주었습니다.
Your Highness is taking refuge now.
전하께서는 지금 피난처를 찾고 계십니다.
endure humiliation
굴욕을 참다
Only then can we have a future
그래야만 우리에게 미래가 있을 수 있다
A day to regain the mountains and rivers
산과 강을 되찾는 날
That day you said
그날 네가 말했지
Commander of the Zhenxi Army Li Ying
진시군 사령관 리잉
He's my seventeenth cousin
그 사람은 내 열일곱 번째 사촌이야
The Zhenxi Army has already left Laolan Pass
Zhenxi 군대는 이미 Laolan Pass를 떠났습니다.
Killed all the way to Wangzhou
왕저우(Wangzhou)까지 살해당함
Brother Seventeen leads the troops
17세 형제가 군대를 이끈다
Still pretty awesome
그래도 꽤 멋지다
I really want to be like him
나는 정말로 그 사람처럼 되고 싶다
Confront the enemy head on
적과 정면으로 맞서라
fight
싸움
The seventeen emperors' grandsons indeed made remarkable achievements in battle
17명의 황제의 손자들은 실제로 전투에서 놀라운 업적을 세웠습니다.
But the Zhenxi Army was originally a government soldier
하지만 Zhenxi 군대는 원래 정부 군인이었습니다.
Pei Xian was not close to the former prince
Pei Xian은 전 왕자와 가깝지 않았습니다.
Your Highness has a distinguished status now
전하께서는 이제 탁월한 지위를 가지셨습니다.
Even if they are blood relatives
혈연관계라도
Don't believe it easily
쉽게 믿지 마세요
What's more, His Royal Highness the King of Liang
게다가 양왕 전하는
He was also detained in West Changjing by Sun Jing
그는 또한 Sun Jing에 의해 West Changjing에 구금되었습니다.
I'm just afraid that Li Yi might have some concerns
리이가 걱정할까봐 걱정이에요
Thinking a lot
생각을 많이 한다
General Han
한 장군
Then when will we
그럼 우리는 언제
Only then can we return to Xichangjing
그래야만 우리는 Xichangjing으로 돌아갈 수 있습니다
There will be that day
그런 날이 있을 거야
I will definitely escort His Highness
반드시 전하를 호위하겠습니다
Return to West Changjing
서창징으로 돌아가기
majestic and majestic
장엄하고 장엄하다
Since Sun Jing raised his army
손징이 군대를 일으킨 이후로
After I left Pingliang
핑량을 떠난 후
never again
다시는
Such an afternoon
그런 오후
can be so comfortable
이렇게 편할 수가 있지
Being able to be with my best friend under the roof
지붕 아래에서 가장 친한 친구와 함께 있을 수 있다는 것
Enjoy the leisurely mood of rain
비오는 날 여유로운 분위기를 즐겨보세요
More rare
더 희귀함
few days ago
몇일 전에
I still dream about returning to Laolan Pass
나는 아직도 라오란 고개로 돌아가는 꿈을 꾼다
I shot a particularly fat yellow sheep
유난히 살찐 노란 양을 쐈어
It's roasting
굽고 있어요
Awakened from the dream
꿈에서 깨어났어요
I'm curious
궁금해
Is Laolan Pass really that good?
라오란패스가 그렇게 좋은가요?
It’s worth remembering you so much
당신을 너무 많이 기억할 가치가 있어요
traces of no-go
가지 않은 흔적
Living without a house
집 없이 살기
Isn't it satisfying?
만족스럽지 않나요?
I invite you to join me in the future
앞으로도 저와 함께 하시길 바랍니다
Go to Laolan Pass
라오란 고개로 이동
would you like
당신은 원하십니까?
You clearly know this is a dream
이건 꿈인 걸 분명히 알잖아
The tree wants to be still but the wind doesn’t stop
나무는 가만히 있고 싶은데 바람이 그치지 않네요
Jushichiro
주시치로
With your current status
현재 상태로는
Can I leave everything behind
모든 걸 뒤로 하고 떠날 수 있을까
Return to the frontier
국경으로 돌아가다
Do you live that kind of life?
당신은 그런 삶을 살고 있습니까?
It's rare to have a good rain
좋은 비가 내리는 경우는 거의 없습니다
Trapping you and me here
너와 나를 여기에 가두어
after the rain stops
비가 그친 후에
It's time to go our separate ways again
이제 다시 각자의 길을 갈 시간이다
let's talk about something else
다른 것에 대해 얘기 해보자
Okay then
알았어 그럼
Tell me about you
너에 대해 말해줘
when you were little
네가 어렸을 때
Are you particularly naughty?
당신은 특히 장난 꾸러기인가요?
More than naughty
장난꾸러기 그 이상
Simply naughty
단순히 장난 꾸러기
My father beat me with the cane
아버지가 지팡이로 나를 때렸어요
I don’t know how many roots were broken.
뿌리가 얼마나 부러졌는지 모르겠습니다.
It seems that His Highness Prince Liang
양 왕자 전하인 것 같습니다
This painstaking discipline
이 힘든 훈련
This has little effect.
이것은 효과가 거의 없습니다.
I'm not afraid of getting beaten
나는 맞을 것을 두려워하지 않는다.
I'm afraid of nagging
잔소리가 두려워
When my mother gave birth to me
엄마가 나를 낳았을 때
Died in childbirth
출산 중 사망
Throughout the palace
궁전 전체에 걸쳐
Only Princess Dong
오직 동 공주만이
Take great care of me
나를 잘 보살펴주세요
My father doesn’t like me
아버지는 나를 좋아하지 않는다
my two brothers
내 두 형제
All relying on father's favoritism
모두 아버지의 편애에 의지하고 있다
I always get beaten up
나는 항상 구타당한다.
It’s been a long time
오랜만이야
My father hates me even more
아버지는 나를 더욱 미워하신다
You frown when you see me
나를 보면 눈살을 찌푸리는 너
Unexpected
예기치 않은
Are you still being bullied like this?
아직도 이렇게 왕따를 당하고 있나요?
My two brothers
나의 두 형제
All were born to Princess Dong
모두 동공주에게서 태어났다
My mother is Princess Dong
우리 엄마는 동공주예요
The maid next to me
내 옆에 있는 메이드
I heard that I was not favored in the past.
과거에는 호의를 받지 못했다고 들었습니다.
Fortunately, Princess Dong
다행히 동 공주는
Take great care of my mother
어머니를 잘 보살펴주세요
After my mother-in-law passed away
시어머니가 돌아가신 후
It was Princess Dong who raised me again
나를 다시 키워준 건 동공주였어
for the princess
공주를 위해
I'm okay with everything
난 모든 게 괜찮아
Don't argue with your brothers
형제들과 논쟁하지 말라
you are a kind hearted person
당신은 마음이 친절한 사람이에요
Others are kind to you
다른 사람들은 당신에게 친절합니다.
You will repay ten points
10포인트를 갚아드립니다
later
나중에
Princess Dong died of illness
동공주가 병으로 사망
I'm at home with nothing to worry about
난 집에 있어 아무 걱정도 하지 않고 있어
I’m also tired of living in Kyoto
나도 교토 생활이 지겨워
I would rather guard the border and defend my homeland.
차라리 국경을 지키고 조국을 지키고 싶습니다.
So I thought of a way
그래서 방법을 생각했어요
Went to Laolan Pass
라오란 고개에 갔다
the day i left
내가 떠난 날
My father and brothers
나의 아버지와 형제들
All very happy
모두 매우 행복합니다
The wet nurse is the only one
젖은 간호사가 유일한 사람입니다
Send me with tears
눈물로 나를 보내소서
Where's the nanny?
유모는 어디 있지?
Are you still in the palace now?
지금도 궁에 계시나요?
she is older
그녀는 나이가 많다
As soon as I left the palace
궁전을 나오자마자
Then send her back to her hometown
그럼 그 사람을 고향으로 돌려보내세요.
Enjoy your family in peace
가족과 함께 편안하게 즐기세요
Fortunately, I left Kyoto
다행히 교토를 떠났어요
Just long time no see
정말 오랜만이군요
I wonder if she is healthy and well
그 사람 건강하고 잘 지내는지 궁금해요
Is there still someone I can remember?
아직도 기억나는 사람이 있나요?
You won't feel lonely
외로움을 느끼지 않을 거예요
My grandma also passed away a long time ago
우리 할머니도 오래 전에 돌아가셨어.
I can barely remember it
기억이 거의 나지 않네요
her look
그녀의 모습
But every time I think of her
하지만 그녀를 생각할 때마다
I feel like she is accompanying me
그녀가 나와 동행하는 것 같은 느낌
I won't feel lonely anymore
더 이상 외롭지 않을 거예요
What kind of person were you when you were a child?
당신은 어렸을 때 어떤 사람이었나요?
I really can't imagine it
정말 상상도 못해요
I guess
내 생각엔
You must be a big brat
넌 큰 놈이 틀림없어
Extremely difficult, right?
매우 어렵죠?
i grew up
내가 자란
He was raised as a boy
그는 소년으로 자랐다
Reading and practicing martial arts
무술을 읽고 연습하기
No different from other boys
다른 남자애들과 다르지 않아
What do boys learn?
소년들은 무엇을 배우나요?
I will learn better than them
나는 그들보다 더 잘 배울 것이다
Your parents forced you to
부모님이 너한테 강요한 거야.
No
아니요
It's my own free will
그건 내 자유 의지야.
I am a girl
나는 소녀이다
The ambition is the same as that of a man
야망은 남자랑 똑같아
Should have put in more effort
더 노력했어야 했는데
OK OK
그래 그래
They all wake up at three o'clock and go to bed at five o'clock.
그들은 모두 3시에 일어나고 5시에 잠자리에 든다.
Sweat more than others
남들보다 땀을 많이 흘린다
Bleed even more
더 많이 피를 흘리세요
sometimes too tired
가끔은 너무 피곤해
injured
다쳐서
Even if it's very hard
많이 힘들어도
I will also endure it silently
나도 묵묵히 견뎌볼게
I don’t even want anyone to know
누구에게도 알리고 싶지 않아
what are you thinking about
당신은 무엇에 대한 생각
I'm thinking
나는 생각 중입니다
If only we had known each other earlier
우리가 좀 더 일찍 서로를 알았더라면
Enough
충분한
Why
왜
This way we can practice martial arts together
이렇게 하면 우리가 함께 무술을 연습할 수 있어요
Read together
함께 읽어보세요
fight together
함께 싸우다
Nothing to do
할 것이 없다
Can we still chat like this?
아직도 이렇게 얘기할 수 있나요?
The rain stopped so quickly
비가 너무 빨리 그쳤어요
Let's go back
돌아가자
good
좋은
I have to say goodbye after seeing you for thousands of miles.
수천 마일 동안 당신을 만나고 작별 인사를 해야 합니다.
Let's go back
돌아가자
I'll give you another ride
다른 차를 태워줄게
Aying
아잉
these twenty years
이 20년
i have never had
나는 한 번도 그런 적이 없다
Like this afternoon
오늘 오후처럼
Peace and joy
평화와 기쁨
Me too
저도요
Wait until the world is at peace
세상이 평화로워질 때까지 기다리세요
You and I are traveling together side by side
너와 나는 나란히 함께 여행하고 있어
It’s a deal
그것은 거래의